Guide to the Stanford Historical Society Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Historical Society records
1979-1995
SC0903
Stanford Historical Society.
4 Linear feet
Records pertain to sponsored events, publications, Stanford historical topics, and other administrative matters and include correspondence, memoranda, minutes, financial records, articles, clippings, and membership card files.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Stanford Historical Society was founded in 1976 to encourage the study and understanding of Stanford University's history and the ideals of the University's founders.
Description of the Collection
Records pertain to sponsored events, publications, Stanford historical topics, and other administrative matters and include correspondence, memoranda, minutes, financial records, articles, clippings, and membership card files.
Access Terms
Stanford Historical Society.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--History.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-1998-043
  - Minutes, Board of Directors, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notices and correspondence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1980-81 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - List of Memorial Plaques on campus (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous items (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Ken and La Verne Wilson, 1985, relating Ken's examination of a gold mining prospect for Lou Henry Hoover in 1935, with a copy of her thank you letter to him and her cook's recipe for heart shaped cookies [all photocopies] (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2008-013
  - A-Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alpha Omega Centennial (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Advertising Course (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Association (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Angel of Grief, 1982-87 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Archives (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - ASSU Council of Presidents (and Senior Class Pres.) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - B-Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bailey, Margery- re possible publication of her letters, 1984-87 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bender Room (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bills Waiting for Expense Report –reconciliation (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Book Sales, mostly of Kiester’s book on D. Tresidder, 1992-93 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bookstore/Art Gallery (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bowman Grove Picnic 8/23/86 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Branner Geneology (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Budget Proposal and Budgets, 1979-93 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Monthly Budget Work Sheets (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Building 310 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Building Plans publication, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bulletin Information (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - C- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1982-93 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - California History Center (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - California Preservation Conference (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cancellations (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Catering (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Centennial Project, correspondence, memos, etc., 1982-91 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Change of Address (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Check Requests (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Civil Engineering: copy of One Hundred Years of Civil Engineering at Stanford and cover letter, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Clock Tower, 1983-85 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Controller’s Office (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Coutts, Peter: copies of historical documents and correspondence re buildings on campus (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - D- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Department of Parks and Recreation (Sacramento Historic Sites) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Durand letters – correspondence re donation of, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - E- Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Emiriti Faculty, lists (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, correspondence, 1981-86 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Expense Statements (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Family Statue, correspondence re, 1987-88 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - F- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Facility Usage (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Finance Committee (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fire House restoration, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Foothills to the Bay (publication), prospectus, 1978, correspondence, 1981-92 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fraternity Houses –San Juan Hill (Preservation) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fremont Historic Building (owned by Stanford) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Funds Invested/ Bascchetti (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - G- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ginzton, Artemus, letters re Memorial for Caroline Charles (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Historical Names (Committee) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Historical Markers (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Honeycutt, Robert (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Honorary Members –Proposals (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Hoover House (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Hoover Institution (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Hopkins, Timothy Room (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Hopkins Marine Station (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - J- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Janss Foundation (Mr. William Janss) – pertains to Kiester’s book on Tresidder, 1990-93 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Jewel Fund and Jewel Fund Booklet (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Jordan, David Starr (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - K- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Kennedy, Donald (President) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Knoles, George (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - L- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Laborde, Mrs. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - L.W. Lane, Jr. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - M- Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Markers (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Matching Grants (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Mausoleum Lighting (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - (Mayfield) Curtain, correspondence, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - McCann, Robert E. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Memorial Church (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Memorial Day Committee (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Memorial File (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - SHS Minutes 1986-92 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Minutes 1994-96 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - N- Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Oak Tree (at Mausoleum?), memo from H. Page re marking a cross section, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Occasional Papers –Bookstore (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - P- Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Palm Drive Entryway, correspondence, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Palo Alto Tree, correspondence, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Peeps, Stephen (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Persky, Phillip (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Publications Sales 1993-95 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Purchase Requisitions (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Quad Renovation (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - R-Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Rains Housing (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Dorothy Regnery (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Roble Hall (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Rodin Garden (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Rosse, James N. Letters (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Row Houses (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - S- Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Senior Plaques (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Serra House (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Servomation Corporation (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Oregon Shakespeare Festival 1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Bidwell (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Budget (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Crater Lake (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Flyer (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 1st Participant Mailing (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Hotel (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Itinerary (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Roster (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Theatre (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Transportation (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Oregon Shakespearean Festival Aug. 18- Aug. 20, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - SLAC Tour (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Stanford Associates (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Stanford Heritage Center (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Leland Stanford Mansion (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Stanford’s Palo Alto Stock Farm (contains copy of D. Regnery’s “French Bronze Horse Statue and the PASF Horse Cemetery,” 1984) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Stakes (horserace) – photo of winning horse and owner, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Stores (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - T-Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Thank You Letters (to members, gift givers, generous…) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Transfer of Expense (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Travis, Maury (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Utah Trip (Centennial) May 1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Vina Ranch clippings (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - W – Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - War Dead Program (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Wakins, James T. IV – Memorial Resolution, clippings, related correspondence (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Weber, David C. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Wilbur, Ray Retiring Letters (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Winbigler, H. Donald (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - “Words Worth A Second Thought” memo re reprinting (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - XYZ- Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Manuscript Draft –Place Names (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Board Members/Roster of Appointments (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Meetings- Agendas and minutes 1987-88 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Meetings- Agendas and minutes 1986-87 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Meetings- Agendas and minutes 1983-87 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Meetings- Agendas and minutes 1982-83 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Meetings- Agendas and minutes 1991-93 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Meetings- Agendas and minutes 1989-91 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Meetings- Agendas and minutes 1987-88 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Membership- January- August 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Financial (assorted) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Deceased- Membership List A-Z (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Membership List A-Z (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Dedication/Gift Cards from Members (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2008-229
  - 1910-1925 Leases and housing fund information copied from Board of Trustee documents (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 715 Salvatierra, draft of description and copies of documents (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Book II [Historic Houses] drafts (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Book IV illustrations (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Book IV – sources at Maps and Records (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - California Historical Buildings Survey (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Charles Kaiser Sumner, Architect (booklet from Palo Alto Stanford Heritage house tour, Dec. 9, 2007) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Early Residences on Stanford University's San Juan Hill (booklet from Palo Alto Stanford Heritage house tour Dec. 12, 2004) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Historic Houses Book II – draft, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Historic Houses – list background (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Historic Houses list (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Historic Houses research guide (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Historic Houses – old list (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Infill housing, 1998-99 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Info on the Row (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Julie C. Lythcott-Haims, Remarks at "Discover Stanford," Sept. 27, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper photocopy, "Homes being built on campus sites" July 24, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Press packet photos on a CD (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Santa Clara County Historical and Genealogical Society 2005 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Santa Clara County Historical Preservation Ordinance, 2003-06 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Campus Residential Leaseholders [SCRL] 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Stanford home (New York), email correspondence, 2005-06 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Stanford obituaries (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Street numbers (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Supplementary information (SCRL) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - William Frederick Durand, biography (Box 2, Folder 7)